Guide to the Mo Willems Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Mo Willems papers
1990-2013
GEN MSS 1003
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
25.63
(32 boxes) + 1 art
Willems, Mo, 1968-
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Box 10 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
February 2017 Acquisition: In-process material. Research use may require advance notice. For further information, consult Access Services.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, artwork, sketchbooks, notebooks, book dummys, proofs, photographs, audiovisual material, electronic media, printed material, merchandise, a drafting table, and other papers by or relating to Mo Willems.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: July 2013 Acquisition; February 2017 Acquisition.
Mo Willems
Mo Willems is an American writer, illustrator, and animator.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Cumberland Rare Books on the Jockey Hollow Fund, 2013, 2017.
Children's literature, American -- 21st century; Illustration of books -- United States; Illustrators -- United States -- 21st century; Born digital; Drawings (visual works); Illustrators; Willems, Mo, 1968-
- July 2013 Acquisition, 1990-2013
  Arrangement
  Organized into four series: I. Writings and artwork, 1999-2013, II. Sketchbooks and notebooks, 1990-2013, III. Merchandise, circa 2000s, IV. Electronic media.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Cumberland Rare Books on the Jockey Hollow Fund, 2013.
  - Writings and artwork, 1999-2013; Series I
    - Dummies and story boards, 1999-2013 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes dummies for Elephant and Piggy! - I am Invited to a Party! (2007), Elephant and Piggy - A Big Guy Took My Ball (2013), Elephant and Piggy - Today I will Fly! (2007), Elephant and Piggy - Can I Play Too (2010), Walter, and The Little Bad Wolf and other early comics (circa 2001) and story boards for Sheep in the Big City (1999-2001) and Time to Say "Please"! (2005).
    - Proofs, drafts, and artwork, 2003-2007 (Box 2 (Oversize))
      Includes proofs, drafts, or artwork for Elephant and Piggie - I Am Invited to a Party! (2007), Leonard, the Terrible Monster (2005), Time To Pee! (2003), and Time To Say "Please"! (2005).
    - Time to Pee! (Box 3)
    - Time to Pee! success chart, 2003 (Box 4 (Oversize))
    - Knuffle Bunny: A Cautionary Musical, binder with working draft, annotated in manuscript, and extensive notes, 2000s (Box 5)
    - Sketchbook, printed ephemera, and photograph of Willems pushing Trixie on a book cart at ALA (Box 6)
  - Sketchbooks and notebooks, 1990-2013; Series II
    Arranged chronologically.
    - "An image a day" travel sketchbook, 1990 (Box 7)
    - "An image a day, vol. II" travel sketchbook, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
    - "An image a day, volume III" travel sketchbook, 1991 (Box 7)
    - The Mo Willems Sketchbook, Vol. 1-20, 1994-2013; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Knuffle Bunney: Musical notebook, 2005-2006 (Box 7)
    - Notebook, 2005 November 18 - 2006 May 28 (Box 7)
    - Notebook, 2006 July - December (Box 7)
  - Merchandise, circa 2000s; Series III
    - Roll of stickers (Box 7)
    - Merchandise featuring Willems characters, circa 2000s (Box 8)
      Includes stuffed animals, a t-shirt, pajamas, sheep toys, and keychain.
    - Knuffle Bunny Free event kit, circa 2000s (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Electronic media, Series IV; 0.21; (1 box) (Box 10)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- February 2017 acquisition, circa 1973-2007; 22; (22 boxes) + 1 art
  In-process material. Research use may require advance notice. For further information, consult Access Services.
  Purchased from Cumberland Rare Books on the Jockey Hollow Fund, 2017.
  Custodial History
  Previously on deposit at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut.
  This acquisition consists of writings, artwork, photographs, electronic media, printed material, film reels, DVDs, CD-ROMs, a drafting table, and other papers by or relating to Mo Willems.